Inventory of the United States Wartime Civil Control Administration miscellaneous records
Hoover Institution Archives
Wartime Civil Control Administration miscellaneous records
1942-1943
68027
United States. Wartime Civil Control Administration.
3 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box (1.7 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives. Stanford, California 94305-6010
Materials relating to the evacuation and relocation of Japanese-Americans in the United States during World War II, including proclamations, orders, memoranda, population statistics, manuals and maps.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1968.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the library catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Historical Note
The Wartime Civil Control Administration operated under the Western Defense Command of the United States Army, provided for the evacuation and temporary resettlement of Japanese and Japanese-Americans in areas of the Pacific coast during World War II. The department oversaw all aspects of the evacuation operations, including assembly centers, transportation, and the transfer of evacuees the jurisdiction of the War Relocation Authority, which was responsible for the relocation, maintenance, and supervision of evacuees and operated the internment camps.
Source: Federal Records of World War II, Vol. II: Military Agencies, Sec. 1096
Scope and Content of Collection
The records relate to the evacuation and relocation of Japanese-Americans in the United States during World War II and include proclamations, orders, memoranda, population statistics, manuals and maps. Materials remain in the original order.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Japanese Americans--Evacuation and relocation, 1942-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--United States.
Collection Contents
- Memoranda, 1942
  - March-April (Folder 1: 1-2)
  - May (Folder 1: 3-4)
  - June-July (Folder 1: 5)
- Transfer orders, 1942 May-October (Folder 1: 6)
- Memoranda to sector commanders, 1942 April-December (Folder 1: 7)
- War Relocation Authority bulletins, 1942 June-December (Folder 1: 8)
- Orders for guard and duty officers, circa 1942 (Folder 1: 9)
- Administrative memoranda and orders, 1942 March-May (Folder 1: 10)
- Wartime Civil Control Administration statistical and evacuation bulletins and supplements, 1942 March-July (Folder 1: 11)
- Japanese relocation, 1942
  - Progress charts, 1942 April 28-August 8 (Folder 1: 12-13)
  - Reports 1-35, 1942 June 15-July 19 (Folder 1: 14)
  - Reports 36-70, 1942 July 20-August 23 (Folder 1: 15)
  - Reports 71-105, 1942 August 24-September 27 (Folder 2: 1)
  - Reports 106-142, 1942 September 28-November 3 (Folder 2: 2)
  - Reports duplicate set, 1-142, 1942 June 15-November 3 (Folder 2: 3)
- National Defense Migration 4th Interim Report, 1942 (Folder 2: 4)
- Civilian exclusion orders, 1942 (Folder 2: 5-7)
- Civilian restrictive orders, 1942-1943 (Folder 2: 8)
- Executive orders, 1942 (Folder 2: 9)
- Public proclamations, 1942 (Folder 2: 10)
- Printed materials, 1942 (Folder 2: 11)
- Center regulations, 1942 (Folder 2: 12)
- Interior security manual, 1942 (Folder 2: 13)
- Operation and maintenance instructions for assembly and reception centers, 1942 (Folder 2: 14)
- Operations manual, June 1942 (Folder 2: 15)
- Operations manual, June 1942 (Folder 4: 1)
- Fiscal guides and procedures, 1942-1943 (Folder 4: 2)
- Instructions governing the interviews of prospective students, 1942 June-July (Folder 4: 3)
- Miscellany, 1942-1943 (Folder 4: 4)
- Oversize maps, circa 1942 (Folder 3)
- Japanese relocation progress chart, circa 1942 (Folder 3)
- Oversize proclamations, circa 1942 (Folder 3)